# R.SHARMILI KAMATCHI

# BUSINESS ANALYST/SCRUM MASTER

#### **PERSONAL HISTORY**

I am a Business Analyst and Certified Scrum Master with 8+ years of experience in IT Industry. Practiced SAFe framework as a Scrum Master for 4+ years in the Industry. Well trained in Business requirement gathering analysis ,documentation and project delivery.

# **TALENTS & SKILLS**

- Highly knowledgeable in business analysis, documentation and project management.
- Mentor Agile Teams towards being more self organised and to work towards releasing on demand.
- Agile and Certified SAFE
- Practitioner.
- Excellent communication skills
- Expert at building rapport with clients and internal Agile Teams.
   Experienced in client demos
- and presentations.
   Servant Leader.
- Project Management tools like JIRA,
- Knowledge on LMS of Home Loans
   User testing and roll out of Projects.

# **CONTACT INFORMATION**

Phone: +91 9840106105

Email:

sharmilikamatchi1992@gmail.com

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sharmili - kamatchi-rengaraj-034872b8/

# **DOMAIN EXPERIENCE**

- Education
- Banking- Home Loans.
- Fintech
- Communications

### PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- SAFe Advanced Scrum Master
- PMI ACP





# **CAREER HISTORY**

# **Assistant Manager - Scrum Master**

TATA Communications | June 2021- Present

- Scrum Master for 5 agile Teams consisting of 4 to 10 members each.
   Manage all SAFe ceremonies such as Iteration planning, Daily stand up Meeting, Iteration Review, Retrospective and PI Planning meetings. Coach the team on SAFe best practises and principles.
- Owning and managing the respective JIRA boards and ensuring it is updated rightly by the team.
- Running PI planning meetings, ensuring all pre-requisites are in place for the team to groom, estimate and plan the PI.
- Part of Scrum of Scrums to resolve dependencies and impediment across cross functional teams.
- Acts as bridge between PMO,PO and the Agile Team.
- Won Individual Performer award twice in my stint in the Agile project delivery category for excellence in my role as a Scrum Master

# **Deputy Manager - Business Analyst**

Cholamandalam Investments and Finance | June 2019-Jan 2021

- Business requirement documentation, analysis for LMS of Home Loans was completely owned.
- Management Presentation and client demos on targets and achievements.
- Played Scrum Master role to run the Project Delivery.

# **Business Analyst**

Bankbazaar.com | Dec 2018 - May 2019

- Managed a agile team of 6 members in driving end to end release independent deliveries.
- Reporting monthly delivery data with retrospectives and RCA.
   Present Business demos to Partner teams and upper management.
- Facilitated requirements and user review sessions withpartner product, technology and credit policy stakeholders.
- Integrating Loan and credit card products on Bankbazaar platform by coordinating with Banks.

#### **Scrum Master**

Pearson English | Nov 2016 - Aug 2018

- Performed as a scrum master for a team of 14 members for a development project on digital classrooms.
- Responsible for all SAFe ceremonies for 3 agile teams. Reported
- Sprint wise delivery reports and also Program Increment wise reports and other Man Days calculation and resource Management reports
- Owned and Managed JIRA for the Project and ensured that all the Project details with respect to all the sprints are updated on the JIRA board story wise. This helps a lot in Project tracking and also managing the capacity and velocity of the team.
- Acted as an Agile Coach by conducting various brainstorming sessions with team regarding Agile Methodologies and SAFe 4.0.

# **Associate Business Analyst**

# Bankbazaar.com | Dec 2014 - Nov 2016

- Performed as a Associate level business analyst in requirement gathering ,analysis and documentation process.
- SOAP UI Testing of web services to integrate with different Banks and Insurance companies.
- · Support on Production support issues and weekly on call support.
- Owned the entire Car Insurance Product and its integration in
- Bankbazaar and worked onboarding several partners on the Platform

# **Associate Software Engineer**

Accenture Services Pvt Ltd | June 2014-Nov 2014

- Worked as a Production support Engineer for a UK based Insurance client
- Worked on reporting of weekly tickets
- · Trained on Mainframes and Cobol Programming

#### **ACADAMIC BACKGROUND**

# **BE - ELECTRONICS AND INSTRUMENTATION ENGINEERING**

UNIVERSITY - RMD Engineering College. YEAR OF PASSING - 2010-2014 SCORE - 8.1 CGPA

#### **HIGHER SECONDARY**

SCHOOL - DAV Higher sec school (Matric) YEAR OF PASSING - 2010 SCORE - 92.41%

# SSLC

SCHOOL - DAV Senior Secondary School(CBSE) YEAR OF PASSING - 2008 SCORE- 90.4%

# **KEY RESULT AREAS**

- Business Analysis and documentation
- Project Delivery
- · Team Management
- Agile Ceremonies and SAFe practises
- · Client Demos and Presentations

# **CAREER FACETS**

- Expert in handling people in different mindsets and posses lot of interest in coaching the teams to make more self organised Teams across the Organisation.
- Knowledge on LOS and LMS of Home loans. Key player in management presentations from the IT front of Home Loans.
- Managed a team of 16 in Pearson, acting as aScrum Master and helped team to practice SAFe 4.0 effectively.
- Managed CR and production support for LMS (Loan management system) of Home loans.
- Ensured timely delivery adhering to all principles of SAFe 4.0
- Worked with partner financial institutions/internal product team in increasing product range offered thereby ensuring better customer engagement and product offering
- Proactively worked with Operations/Account Management/Category
  Management team using numbers, analytics, problem solving to increase
  conversions and also increase visibility for various partners in BankBazaar
  platform
- Instrumental in implementation of Insurance platform in BankBazaar.

# **PERSONAL DETAILS**

DATE OF BIRTH: 13th May 1992

**AGE**: 30

**GENDER:** Female

MARITAL STATUS: Married

LANGUAGES KNOWN: English, Tamil, Telugu

COUNTRY : India STATE : Tamil Nadu CITY : Chennai